coalitional game theory is an approach
联盟博弈论是一种方法
to modeling strategic situations that
对战略形势进行建模
stands in contrast was usually called
相反，通常称为
non cooperative game theory and in fact
非合作博弈论，实际上
coalitional game theory is often called
联盟博弈理论通常被称为
cooperative game theory the names are
合作博弈论的名字是
luminous reading and I'll get back to
夜光阅读，我会回到
that in a moment but let's first speak
片刻之后，让我们先说
about what situations does coalitional
关于什么情况联盟
game theory try to model you may
博弈论尝试为您建模
recognize these two fine-looking
认出这两个好看的
gentlemen the person on the left is
先生们，左边的人是
David Cameron Prime Minister of Britain
英国首相戴维·卡梅伦
and to his to his right as we look at it
看着他在他右边
he's left as they sit is Nicholas Clegg
当他们坐下时，他离开的是尼古拉斯·克莱格
his cultural partner now here are two
他的文化伙伴现在有两个
political rivals who nonetheless come
仍然来的政治对手
together and presumably there's a reason
在一起，大概是有原因的
there's something where they can
他们可以在某些地方
accomplish together that they cannot
一起完成，他们不能
accomplish alone in particular in this
尤其是独自完成
case command a majority in the in the
case命令中的大多数
parliament and so that's a classical
议会，所以这是经典
example where a coalition formed in fact
实际上组成联盟的例子
we usually when you think about
我们通常在您想到的时候
coalition we think about political
我们考虑政治的联盟
parties but coalition's form not only in
政党，但联盟的形式不仅在
politics they certainly form in business
他们在业务中形成的政治
so the wind coalition is a the coming
因此，风电联盟即将到来
together of a number of firms in the
多家公司
United States to promote the joint
美国联合推广
agenda of wind energy turbines and such
风力发电机等的议程
again these are companies who are
这些都是公司
competitors and nonetheless they feel
竞争对手，尽管如此
that together there's things that can
在一起的东西可以
exist do that they can't do alone
存在，他们不能一个人做
for example Lobby government established
例如建立游说政府
standards and things of that nature
这种性质的标准和事物
now coalition's aren't always among
现在联盟并不总是
organizations or parties of ferns or
蕨类植物的组织或团体或
heavyweight things we as individuals
作为个人的重量级事物
routinely come together to accomplish
经常聚在一起完成
things
东西
together whether it's to enter in
一起进入
marriage or for example build a house
结婚或盖房子
when you have a carpenter Ln efficient
当你有一个木匠Ln高效
and a painter that come together they
和一个画家在一起
together can accomplish something that
一起可以完成一些
they can't on their own now the mere
他们现在不能只靠自己
fact that people come together doesn't
人们聚在一起的事实
mean that their interests are aligned or
表示他们的利益一致或
that they bring the same amount of value
他们带来相同的价值
to the coalition they've formed it could
他们组成的联盟可以
be for example that the framer of a
例如，
construction crew is irreplaceable
施工人员是不可替代的
but electricians are easy to find and
但是电工很容易找到
one could easily replace and presumably
一个可以轻松替换，大概
when they get paid for the house they
当他们得到房子的报酬时
build that should be reflected in how
建立应该反映在如何
they divide the the payment and so
他们分摊付款，所以
there's a competition of both
两者都有竞争
cooperation and competition here and and
合作与竞争在这里和
so for that reason calling these
所以出于这个原因
cooperative games as the common term is
合作游戏是通用术语
it is a little misleading just as much
同样有点误导
as non cooperative game theories
作为非合作博弈论
misleading as well because for example
也会引起误解，例如
if you look at the normal form game the
如果你看普通的形式游戏
canonical representation of a non
非的规范表示
cooperative game one can easily describe
合作游戏可以轻松描述
a completely harmonious situation of
完全和谐的情况
so-called team gains or common payoff
所谓的团队收益或共同收益
games where the interests of the ages
历代利益的游戏
are completely aligned so both non
完全对齐
cooperative game theory and coalitional
合作博弈论与联盟
or cooperative game theory model both
或合作博弈模型
competition and coordination the
竞争与协调
essential difference is the basic
基本区别是基本
modeling unit in coalitional game theory
联盟博弈模型的建模单元
the basic modeling unit is the group the
基本建模单位是
team and what they kind of can
团队，他们能做什么
accomplish and the analysis is based on
完成，分析基于
this basic modeling
这个基本的模型